Finding aid to the Edith Naomi Hill Papers CA.MS.00121
Smith College Archives
Edith Naomi Hill Papers
1913-1975
Smith College Archives
Hill, Edith Naomi, 1881-1975.
CA.MS.00121
0.417 linear feet (1 container)
Editor-in-Chief of the Smith Alumnae Quarterly. Contains biographical materials, correspondence, photographs, newspaper clippings, speeches, and publications.
Biographical / Historical
Edith Naomi Hill was born on April 10, 1881 in Chicago, Illinois to parents Calvin H. and Naomi (Childs) Hill. She was educated at Miss Capen's Boarding School in Northampton, MA and eventually went on to graduate from Smith College in 1903. From 1908 to 1910, Hill attended Columbia University, studying History, English, and Philosophy. Also in 1910, she became Editor in Chief of the Smith Alumnae Quarterly, which had been established only a year earlier. In 1928, Hill was granted an Honorary Master of the Arts Degree by President W.A. Neilson of Smith College. Ten years later, in 1938, Hill retired from her position at the Alumnae Quarterly, but continued to work in the publications department until 1952. She devoted much of her energy and efforts to the students of Smith College, and was an active member of the Northampton community. On crutches since childhood, she fought ill health and failing eyesight her entire life, until April 9, 1975. She passed away one day short of her 94th birthday in the Amherst Nursing Home.
Scope and Contents
This collection includes biographical materials, correspondence, photographs, newspaper clippings, speeches and publications relating to Hill's career at Smith College and elsewhere.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for use without restriction beyond the standard terms and conditions of Smith College Special Collections.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Edith Naomi Hill Papers were donated over a period of time to the Smith College Archives from a variety of sources.
Hill, Edith Naomi, 1881-1975.
- Capen Boarding School, 1952 (Box 867, Folder 1)
- Capen School Photo Album, undated (Box 867, Folder 2)
- Editor - Smith Alumnae Quarterly, 1913-1975 (Box 867, Folder 3)
- Honorary Degree, 1928 (Box 867, Folder 4)
- The Innocent, 1967 (Box 867, Folder 5)
- Photographs, 1928-1956 (Box 867, Folder 6)
- Speeches, 1935-1959 (Box 867, Folder 7)
- Speeches - Hop Scotching Alum, 1936-1956 (Box 867, Folder 8)
- Publications - Faith Builds a College, 1950 (Box 867, Folder 9)
- Publications - Magic Carpets, 1950-1960 (Box 867, Folder 10)
- Publications - Page Gerturde Bell, 1957 (Box 867, Folder 11)
- Publications - Poems, 1946 (Box 867, Folder 12)
- Publications - Senda Berenson, undated (Box 867, Folder 13)
- Publications - Wartime Report, 1943 (Box 867, Folder 14)